https://edalliance.org/about-ea/privacy-policy/

PRIVACY POLICY
Effective as of: February 28, 2019
Educational Alliance (“EA”) is committed to protecting the personal information that you provide and entrust to us when using our website. This online privacy statement (the “Privacy Statement”) describes how we treat all user data collected by EA during your visit to the EA Site, both technical data that is automatically collected and voluntarily submitted data.
For purposes of this Privacy Statement, the “EA Site” is the website whose home page is www.edalliance.org. Additionally, this is not the privacy statement for internet sites (e.g. social networking sites) where EA has a presence that are on websites other than the EA Site.
Educational Alliance may occasionally update this Statement. We will post any changes on this web page, so be sure to check back periodically. Any information that you submit after a change has been posted will be subject to the new provisions.
User Data We Collect
We collect two types of user data: (1) technical data that is automatically collected from all visitors to the EA Site (“Automatically Collected Data”); and (2) data that you voluntarily submit to us (described below under “Voluntarily Submitted Data”).
Automatically Collected Data.
We automatically collect and store Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses and domain names of the originating visitor’s computer on our server and may know some information you have previously provided through cookies. (See the section on “Cookies” below for more information.) We also track the number and frequency of hits per page, as well as length of website visit, using IP addresses and/or session cookies. In addition, if you come to the EA Site from a website link, we may also identify the source of that link.
Voluntarily Submitted Data.
We may collect and store Voluntarily Submitted Data, including personal data, that you voluntarily provide, such as your name and postal address, phone number, e-mail address, and similar information, and transactional information when you participate in certain activities on the EA Site, including (but not limited to) when you:
make a contribution to support Educational Alliance;
sign up for our e-mails;
register online for an event;
submit feedback to EA; or
participate in any activity that requires your Voluntarily Submitted Data.
Cookies
We collect some data through the use of cookies. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that are transferred to your computer’s hard drive and either stored permanently for future access by the transferor (“Long-term Cookies”) or temporarily to facilitate the transferor’s website analysis and functionality (“Short-term Cookies”) or that are transferred temporarily to your computer’s Random Access Memory (“Session Cookies”).
We may use Session Cookies whenever you visit the EA Site for our website traffic analytics application. Session Cookies last only as long as your session on the EA Site. They expire when the session ends and are not written onto your computer’s hard drive. We also use Session Cookies in e-mails containing the HTML-format. If you select “text-only” format preference, emails sent to you will not contain any Session Cookies.
Some of our website analysis and functionality, such as maps and videos, are provided through third-party functionality and require the use of Short-term Cookies. These Short-term Cookies are set to expire within one hour of their being placed on your hard drive.
Some elective, third-party media functionality on the EA Site may also use Cookies. Please see the “Third Parties—Third-Party Functionality” section below.
How We Use The Data We Collect
In addition to the uses described above, we use Automatically Collected Data to identify the source outside the EA site of user traffic (for example, unhnyc.org, or google.com) so that we can evaluate what content is persuading web users to become involved in the EA’s work. We use Automatically Collected Data, including IP addresses and/or session or short-term cookies, that indicates which sections of the EA Site are most visited so that we can perform website traffic analysis, evaluate the popularity of our different web pages and continue to improve the EA Site in order to learn which EA website content inspired you to engage in our organization. Automatically Collected Data also may be associated with the Voluntarily Submitted Data you provide to us to detect security intrusions or certain unlawful activity.
We use your Voluntarily Submitted Data for various purposes:
To fulfill the request for which you specifically provided the data, including sharing the data with its intended recipient;
To periodically communicate with you concerning EA matters, such as delivering to you information and updates on our activities, if you have not opted out of receiving such information and updates;
To offer you other ways to support EA, including solicitations for additional contributions if you have not opted out of receiving such communications;
To confirm your contribution to the EA;
To confirm your registration to an EA event;
To respond to an inquiry or feedback you have made to the EA; and
To follow up with you with an email specific to an activity you have participated in or intend to participate in.
The EA Site is hosted by servers in the United States. Accordingly, if you are located outside of the United States, the Voluntarily Submitted Data you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. By submitting your Voluntarily Submitted Data, you consent to its transfer and storage in the United States and its use in accordance with the purposes for which it was originally collected (see below regarding third-party sharing of Voluntarily Submitted Data from non-U.S. residents).
If you are a U.S. resident, we may also from time to time combine your Voluntarily Submitted Data with some publicly available data collected from third parties to improve our services to you and for our own internal marketing, communications, and fundraising purposes.
Third Parties
Third Party SharingWe will not share your Voluntarily Submitted Data with any third party unless we first notify you and offer you an appropriate choice to consent to such further use, for example, through an opt-out or opt-in request.
Third-Party FunctionalityAs discussed in the preceding section, to support certain functions carried out on the EA Site, the EA uses third-party service providers. In limited instances with respect to specific optional functions on the EA Site, those third parties may have data collection, use or security procedures that differ from the practices outlined in this Privacy Statement and that may impact users of those optional functions. For example, a third-party service provider may support a specific web tool on the EA site, such as a web game that appears within the EA Site, even though that tool is actually on the website of the third-party service provider. Any time a third-party service provider’s data collection, use or security practices differs from the data collection/use practices described in this Statement in a manner that would impact users of the EA Site, we will either describe on the page of the EA Site where such optional functions appear the specific data collection, use or security practices of such third-party service provider that would apply if you elect to use that optional function or we will provide a link to that third-party service provider’s privacy policy.
Your Ability to Choose
On our website you have the option of providing your first name, last name and email address to join our mailing list. If you wish to unsubscribe, by clicking the opt-out option at the end of an email or you can send an email to info@edalliance.org. Again, please remember that if you are a non-U.S. resident, we will not use your Voluntarily Submitted Data for any purpose other than the one for which it was originally collected regardless of whether you check or un-check a box.
Children
We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13.
Security
The Voluntarily Submitted Data we collect about you is stored on a secure, password protected server and only authorized personnel have access to your information. We use industry-standard encryption technologies with respect to the receipt and transfer of Voluntarily Submitted Data you submit to us on the EA Site and only authorized personnel have access to your information. Because standard email is unencrypted, encryption is not used in any e-mail functionality. Nevertheless, despite our best efforts, no transmission over the Internet and no data storage method can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.
Comments and Questions
If you have any questions, comments or concerns about this Privacy Statement or our data collection practices or to request that we delete your Voluntarily Submitted Data, you can send us your questions or comments via email to info@edalliance.org.
Donors
Educational Alliance has a commitment to never sell or trade our donor’s personal information to another organization nor send mailings to our donors on behalf of other organizations. This applies to all information received by Educational Alliance through any platform whether online or through a physical donation. In the event that a donation is processed through a third-party service provider, our donors’ information will be used for payment processing only when necessary.
We reserve the right to revise this Donor Policy at any time by updating this posting. Changes to this policy can be determined by review the Effective Date listed below.
Effective 2/28/19
